A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 3255-6261 FA739B
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Program review: Bangladesh (Reports 006234), 1981; Available as Microfiche only (Box 915)
  Charity organization -- Bangladesh; Economic assistance -- Bangladesh; Endowments -- Bangladesh -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Bangladesh; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Ford Foundation Management
- Program review: Mexico and Central America, Novemer (Reports 006235), 1981; Available as Microfiche only (Box 915)
  Charity organization -- Mexico; Charity organization -- Central America; Economic assistance -- Mexico; Economic assistance -- Central America; Endowments -- Mexico -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Central America -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Mexico; Philanthropy; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation Management
- Workshop for population education program planners, East-West Center, Hawaii (Reports 006236), 1972
  Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Program review: Andean Region and Southern Cone (Reports 006237), 1981; Available as Microfiche only (Box 915)
  Charity organization -- Andes Region; Charity organization -- Southern Cone of South America; Charity organization -- Latin America; Economic assistance -- Andes Region; Economic assistance -- Southern Cone of South America; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation Management
- Program review: Brazil (Reports 006238), 1981; Available as Microfiche only (Box 915)
  Charity organization -- Latin America; Economic assistance -- Latin America; Philanthropy -- Latin America; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Ford Foundation. Brazil Office; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Ford Foundation Management
- Materials for Southeast Asia field office presentation (Reports 006239), 1981; Available as Microfiche only (Box 915)
  Charity organization -- Southeast Asia; Economic assistance -- Southeast Asia; Philanthropy -- Southeast Asia; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Ford Foundation. Southeast Asia; Ford Foundation. Field Office Jakarta; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Ford Foundation Management
- Program review: Middle East and North Africa (Reports 006240), 1981; Available as Microfiche only (Box 915)
  Charity organization -- Middle East; Charity organization -- Africa, North; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa, North; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa, North -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Ford Foundation Management
- Program review: Eastern and Southern Africa (Reports 006241), 1981; Available as Microfiche only (Box 915)
  Charity organization -- Africa, East; Charity organization -- Africa, Southern; Endowments -- Africa, East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa, Southern -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Philanthropy -- Africa; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Ford Foundation Management
- Program review: India, Nepal, Sri Lanka (Reports 006242), 1981 (Box 280)
  various pagings: ill., map, tables
  Charity organization -- Southeast Asia; Endowments -- Southeast Asia -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Philanthropy -- Southeast Asia; Ford Foundation. Field Office New Delhi; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Ford Foundation Management
- Program reviews: background material (Reports 006243), 1981 (Box 280)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Charity organization -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation Management
- Visit to Ahmadu Bello University March 14-15, 1968 (Reports 006244) (Box 280)
  Universities and colleges -- Kenya; Education, Higher -- Kenya; Veterinary medicine -- Study and teaching -- Kenya; Veterinarians -- Training of -- Kenya; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Kenya; Ahmadu Bello University; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Thoughts on international division programming following the Conference of International Women's Year, Auguast (Reports 006245), 1975 (Box 280)
  Memo to David Bell dated August 25, 1975.
  International Women's Year, 1975; Women -- Developing countries; Women -- Services for -- Developing countries; Women in development -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Second India series: Population (Reports 006246), 1976 (Box 280)
  Brief review and synopsis of Jaipal P. Ambannavar's Population volume of the Second India series.[…]Memo to John Bresnan and Kit Miller, dated January 13, 1976.
  Second India series
  Population research -- India
- My work in the next two years (Reports 006247), 1975 (Box 280)
  4 p. + attachment.
  Women -- Research -- Developing countries; Women -- Services for -- Developing countries; Women in development -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Summary tables, FY 1973 and earlier years (Reports 006248), 1974 (Box 280)
  [21 p.]: principally tables
- Implications of the Mexico Conference for International Division Programming (Reports 006249), 1975 (Box 280)
  Women in development -- Developing countries; Women -- Services for -- Developing countries; Rural women -- Services for -- Developing countries; Feminism -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Updated list of trustee-related organizations (Reports 006250), 1976 (Box 280)
  Memo to Executive Officers, POICs, and Heads, dated June 7, 1976.
  1 p. + attachment
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Administration; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation. Office of the Secreatary
- Heard on cultural activities (II) (Reports 006251), 1974 (Box 280)
  International Division/HA
  Anthropology -- Research -- Latin America; Cultural property -- Latin America; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Humanities and the Arts
- Final report of the Church committee (Reports 006252), 1976 (Box 280)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Intelligence service -- United States; Ford Foundation. Office of the President; Ford Foundation Management; United States. Central Intelligence Agency
- Notes on North and West Africa (Reports 006253), 1968 (Box 280)
  International Division/Middle East and Africa/Office of the Vice President
  Charity organization -- Africa, West; Charity organization -- Africa, North; Technical assistance -- Africa, West; Technical assistance -- Africa, North; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Affirmative action and Foundation grantees, November 15 (Reports 006254-001), 1972 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Memo to Howard Dressner dated November 15, 1972. Includes Possible approaches for the establishment and application of standards.
  Ford Foundation External Affirmative Action Program
- Affirmative action, June 27 (Reports 006254-002), 1973 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Included: Cover memo (June 27, 1973). Missing second memo reporting on the first twelve months of Ford Foundation's Internal Affirmative Action Program.
- External affirmative action initiative, October 12 (Reports 006254-003), 1973 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Memo from McGeorge Bundy to Ford Foundation staff (October 12, 1973)
- External affirmative action initiative, September 25 (Reports 006254-004), 1973 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Memo from Howard Dressner to the Trustees (September 25, 1973) enclosing proposed policy and guidelines for the external affirmative action initiative. Includes Grantee organizations consulted on proposed policy and guidelines (listing).
- External affirmative action, statement in grant letter (Reports 006254-005), 1980 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Staff memoranda from Howard Dressner and Willard Hertz regarding the continuation of the Foundation's external affirmative action program.
- External affirmative action - evaluation steps, April 22 (Reports 006254-006), 1975 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Memo to executive officers, heads and POICs.
- External affirmative action, October 13 (Reports 006254-007), 1977 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Memo from Howard Dressner to Ford Foundation staff enclosing the modified statement of the External Affirmative Action Program. Includes appendix: Federal laws and executive orders relating to job discrimination.
  Affirmative action programs -- United States; Discrimination in employment -- United States; Diversity in the workplace -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States; Women -- Employment -- United States; Minorities -- Employment; Ford Foundation. External Affirmative Action Program
- Affirmative action and Foundation grantees, August 14 (Reports 006254-008), 1972 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Memo to Howard Dressner dated August 14, 1972. Includes Possible approaches.
- External affirmative action initiative: progress report, March 25 (Reports 006254-009), 1974 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Memo from Willard Hertz to Howard Dressner dated March 25, 1974.
- External affirmative action program basic documents (Reports 006254-010), 1980 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Comprised of 14 basic documents dating from 1972 to 1980 on the development of the Ford Foundation's external affirmative action initiative for grantees. A detailed list of the basic documents is located at the front of the report.
  External Affirmative Action Program
  Affirmative action programs -- United States; Discrimination in employment -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States; Diversity in the workplace -- United States; Ford Foundation. External Affirmative Action Program
- External affirmative action (Reports 006254-011), 1974 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Reprinted from Ford Foundation letter, June 15, 1974.
- External affirmative action: a review of the first 18 months (Reports 006254-012), 1975 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
- The Foundation's external affirmative action program, August 22 (Reports 006254-013), 1979 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Memo to Franklin Thomas (August 22, 1979).
- The Foundation's external affirmative action program (Reports 006254-014), 1977 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
  Memo to officers (September 1, 1977). Also included: Memo from Willard Hertz (August 30, 1977), External Affirmative Action Program: progress report, and Selected RGA statements.
- External affirmative action initiative: progress report, December 6 (Reports 006254-015), 1973 (Box 280, Reel R-9302)
- A time to choose: summary of final report of the Energy Policy Project (Reports 006255), 1974 (Box 280)
  Energy Policy Project
  Energy policy -- United States; Energy policy -- Economic aspects -- United States; Ford Foundation. Energy Policy Project; Ford Foundation. Resources and the Environment
- Survey of needs and opportunities for assistance to population studies as related to development planning in Southeast Asia: date for item II in outline of tasks for Ford Foundation (Reports 006256), 1962 (Box 280)
  16 p.: maps, tables
  Data for item II in outline of tasks for Ford Foundation...
  Population research -- Southeast Asia
- Minorities and mathematics (Reports 006257), 1981 (Box 280)
  Reviews lessons learned from nine grants made to improve the mathematical competence of male and female minority students. […]Reviews lessons learned from nine grants made to improve the mathematical competence of male and female minority students.
  Minorities -- Education, Higher -- United States -- Congresses; Mathematics -- Study and teaching -- United States -- Congresses; African American universities and colleges -- Curricula; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Curricula; Ford Foundation. Education and Research
- A microeconomic analysis of production behavior of the farm household in Japan: a profit function approach (Reports 006258), 1976 (Box 280)
  07200432
  Research on distributional effects of agricultural change in Southeast Asia.
  40 p. + attachment.
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Japan; Agricultural productivity -- Japan; Farms, Small -- Japan; The Leland Stanford Junior University
- Hacia una economia de libre mercado: Chile 1974-1979 / Towards a free market economy: Chile 1974-1979 (Reports 006259), 1980 (Box 280)
  58 p.: tables
  Economics -- Research -- Chile; Economics -- Political aspects -- Chile; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- The Ford Foundation's language activities, September 9-10, 1971 (Reports 006260) (Box 280)
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Africa, East; English language -- Study and teaching -- Africa, Central; English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers; Endowments -- Africa, East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa, Central -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Education and Research
- Notes on the rural economy of the People's Republic of China (Reports 006261), 1980 (Box 281)
  Notes from the following Ford members: Lowell S. Hardin, Reed Hertford, Dwight H. Perkins, and Sumter L. Travers.
  Rural development -- China; Social sciences -- Research -- China; Agriculture -- Research -- China; Charity organization -- China; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific